so I'm very happy to introduce our next
speaker today we've got ashw shavasan
who's going to be talking
about um leveraging user Behavior
insights to enhance search relevance and
for those of you who don't know uh Ubi
is a really exciting project that we've
actually been working with the open
search team on uh at open source
connections and one of those ideas is
that when you understand it you think
why hasn't this been done before um and
it's wonderful to to uh to hear a bit
more about it so ashwath is a uh senior
search engine architect at AWS he's been
working in search as a search engineer
for several years in use cases like
e-commerce search Enterprise search site
search um and yes he's currently working
on open search so without further Ado
I'm going to hand over to Ashworth Round
of Applause thank you Charlie
I hope the folks in the zoom are able to
hear me uh put in the chat if you don't
uh good morning good afternoon good
evening wherever you are joining from uh
my name is ashwat and I am going to talk
about uh
leveraging Ubi user be Behavior insight
to enhance your such relevancy uh
today um I I mean uh um having worked
with several search engines uh for
several such use cases over the past
several years I am currently focusing my
attention my uh effort towards open sech
uh these days I'm quite glad about it
and and how is open SAR doing open
suchar is a little over three years old
right
now with over uh 700 million downloads
ranking fourth in the DB engines ranking
with uh 80 different partners and
growing every day and with multiple uh
major Cloud providers such as AWS which
is where I'm employed Oracle um oy cloud
huawe cloud and Azure and gcp Via our
partners uh offering managed solutions
for open
search and uh if you have not seen the
announcement um open search is now
software Foundation uh under the Linux
foundation and with all these things um
I'm happy to say that we are doing
pretty good yeah um and I'm not sure if
you're able to capture the color scheme
compatibility between open search uh and
the Linux
Foundation uh I think this was meant to
happen yeah so once again I'm pretty
glad that this happened so any questions
about uh how open sources open S is
already I think self anwered yeah
so uh in this talk I would be talking
about uh Ubi uh user Behavior insights
or UB that's what we call it uh the why
uh what does Ubi provide uh Ubi with
open search how do you use Ubi with open
search and Beyond open search and the
Art of the possibilities uh with Ubi um
oh unfortunately I have not stopped uh
started my time so give me just one
second
I'm also having the same screen so I
don't have the time yeah but I'm hoping
someone can
okay uh why Ubi um uh unlike in the
database world where a good result is
well defined uh often in such world is
not the case yeah uh everyone wants the
best result right but the best is very
related to best uh according to whom
best according to you or your product
managers or your business or your
relevancy Engineers yeah uh but maybe
users uh I think they are the end Target
so uh if we somehow capture what the
users are doing uh we should be able to
infer what is good yeah so that is the
whole point of Ubi so that's the uh
bottom line of Ubi at least at this
point um and with this strong
justification or at least I hope I will
move on to the Ubi goals um the goals
for Ubi is to collect data so we collect
data set okay I I try not to say we but
uh so we don't collect the data so you
collect the data you own the data so you
control the data so you're not giving
the data to anyone yeah let me put it
out there so with Ubi the data that is
collected um or such as what are the
searches that are being done yeah uh did
the user use the type ahead feature uh
did the user click on the facet refiner
to filter the search yeah or did they
click on a search result did they not
click on a search result are several
users not clicking on the same search
result maybe it's an anomaly listing
that shouldn't even be uh there in a
search results in the first page yeah
and also things like um uh what are the
sequence uh in which the searches are
executed how are they related to each
other um and also maybe things like um
how long it took for the search to show
up yeah and also uh another thing is um
suchar backwards in the sense uh when a
purchase is made how do we know what was
the suchar journey so how did someone
end up making a purchase so these are
the kind of data that uh Ubi collects um
and and of course yeah I mean some of
you or many of you have this uh question
uh yeah I mean there are several uh
tools out there uh Google analytics or
core metrics or snowplow right um they
do capture what the users are doing uh
how long are they in the the dwell time
how long are they there uh what did they
click on did they click on the back
button and things like that but often I
mean in in the context of search for a
non-static page such as a suchar resar
page right often times the metrics that
are captured by these generic tools are
very noisy uh you give this data to your
suchar engineer they probably are going
to want the data engineer to clean up
the data before even they can make sense
out of this data yeah so once again so
this is the whole point of Ubi um Ubi is
the kind of data collected by the search
Engineers for the search Engineers so it
cannot get any more tailor made uh than
this
yeah uh and if you're still not
convinced probably you are from tra
stock uh but if you're still not I mean
as a such engineer you probably are
using several of these tools or such
components you're using quy or you're
trying to integrate the semantic search
you are doing some kind of hybrid search
lexical and semantic Canon search or
you're using neural SP search I mean you
can do all you want but how would you
know if you're making your search Better
or Worse right I mean um you can do um
uh evaluation tools you can use
evaluation tools uh you can do AB
testing create judgment list right but
measuring and tracking user Behavior
acts as a source for anything that is
listed in here so once again that is why
Ubi and once you are able to do this you
able to tune your search based on
whatever you have understood from here
and the cycle goes on
yeah um what does Ubi provide at its
core uh Ubi provides the standardized
schema so that is the um
fundamental uh thing that Ubi provides a
standardized schema uh it also provides
client side instrumentation uh a bunch
of javascripts yeah uh it also provides
uh tools to collect the generated data
and it also provides the means to
analyze the collected data so this is
the scope at least for now once again
for Ubi uh so these are the Ubi
priorities and
um anytime uh anyone talking about
standardizing the schema this meme uh
shows up yeah um lucky for us um the
Isis no competing schema at least at
this point in the context of such um so
yeah uh once again lucky for us but I
hope it Remains the Same for the coming
days coming several years down the line
yeah uh zooming in uh getting into the
technicals uh Ubi um at least in open
search right now uh is uh there as two
indices uh the query index and the
events index uh pretty self-explanatory
uh on the queries index uh we are going
to store uh the search queries that are
uh being done so you're going to lock
the search queries and on the events
index is where the click metrics go what
is the user doing and so on and so forth
yeah uh zooming in further I hope uh it
is legible enough uh looking at this
this is the standardized schema that we
have uh for the queries index and if you
look at it we have the client ID which
captures I also have a uh example
document in here so the client ID
captures the user uh identifies the user
in a combination with what um browser or
what fron or application mobile or
desktop yeah such kind of information
can go there uh the query which is where
you log the entire query in the context
of um open search we have the entire
open search DSL query being locked here
so you can simply I mean copy and paste
uh and rerun the query at a later point
in when you need it right uh query
attributes as you see it's a flat object
which means it can take uh once again in
open search it can take entire Jason uh
so anything that is not captured as a
part of the Ubi queries can actually go
there um as you can see here in this
example uh there is application name uh
within the query attributes and then the
query ID um important one which is where
we actually identify what is the query
so so you have to reuse the query ID if
you have to um track the user Journey or
the search Journey yeah so that's why
query ID is uh super important in this
uh uh schema the response ID hits is
where you lock the doc IDs that were
sent as a part of the search so a search
has been made doc IDs are written to the
uh user so those IDs uh go there only
those ones that are um uh seen on the
search resarch page go there yeah
um time uh yeah time stamp which is once
again uh the time at which the search
has happened and the user query which is
basically the search term that was used
iPhone or tablet or notebook or whatever
that was being searched yeah uh on the
events index um we have the action name
action name takes in uh what action was
performed was it on search or was it on
the click on a facet was it on a uh was
it a usage of a typ ahead so those
things can go there um application the
same as the Ubi queries application the
application name client ID once again
the same identifying the user with the
combination of what how they're using
your uh uh
portal um even attributes I will come
back to this uh message can take as in
this example um uh it STS the item that
was clicked the search result uh the
title of the search result that was
clicked
um and we have the query ID once again
the same query ID that you used in the
Ubi query index and the time stamp once
again when the event happens so if you
look at it right um both uh the queries
and the events index uh carry time stamp
the current time when the uh action was
performed which also means you can treat
both both these indices As Time series
data yeah
so uh going back to the event attributes
so anything that you think is not
captured is not available as a part of
the schema anything else that you want
to capture can go uh in the EV
attributes yeah um so basically this is
where you can go
wild uh but this is also where uh
mapping explosion can happen so which
means you have to find the balance
between uh these two
yeah um oh uh so uh even attribute some
example uh what was the position of the
search result that was clicked what was
the pos position on the screen that was
clicked such informations yeah and there
are more things like uh dwel time and
things that are being captured in this
example yeah uh Ubi with open search um
uh I will quickly talk about the data
flow in here um so Ubi in open search is
a plug-in yeah uh so you have to install
the plugin with open search um um to use
Ubi uh in this Clow diagram we have the
sear and point which is there in uh open
suchar and we have the Ubi queries uh
index here the events index in here and
uh you have the search box over there
and someone is performing a search your
user is performing a search the search
is now served uh the Ubi plugin
identifies that a search request has
been made and it is logging the search
request in the Ubi query uh index yeah
now the search is now executed doc IDs
are sent back to the user the Ubi
plug-in not only captures the search
request that was uh made it also locks
the doc IDs that were sent as a part of
the search request in the same document
yeah um now uh uh the user is performing
some action they are clicking on certain
results uh they're interacting with your
uh uh such results let's say they click
on one of the results so this is where
you lock this data onto the Ubi uh
events index you using those client side
uh uh instrumentation unlike the Ubi
queries where you send the request as it
is and the plugin takes care of logging
the search request into the U queries
index for the events you have to use the
client side instrumentation the
JavaScript that I would show you uh to
directly pass that uh information to the
Ubi event index
yeah now the uh user has gone to the
details page they click on let's say uh
add to card or uh review views or
whatnot so those events are once again
captured into the Ubi events index so
this is one way of doing it and U you
can um on open search you can actually
get uh in your real time of whatever is
happening uh however the user is
interacting with your uh such
application uh but you can also in order
to scale uh what you can do is iner of
sending the uh client side information
or uh the events information instead of
sending directly to open search you can
use um staging data prepper data prepper
is a lightwe if you do not know it's a
light white the data processing tool in
the open search ecosystem yeah so you
can lock those you can go via data
proper and then batch it up and then put
it to the Ubi events index yeah another
advantage of doing this is basically if
you have some uh critical information
that is not exposed in the front end
let's say profit margin product profit
margin which is basically not available
in the front end unless you want someone
to hack and know your information so
these information exist somewhere else
let's say Dynamo DB or your file system
or anywhere yeah so what you can
actually do is when you get the events
as and when you get the events you get
the corresponding uh s sensitive
information from from wherever they are
stored so this is where you can use to
uh merge the data as one data and put it
back to your uh events index yeah
so this is the data flow and now I would
show you how this happens uh in open
search so I'm not sure how many of you
are familiar with the open sarch
dashboards this is the
visualization a dashboarding uh element
of open search yeah um so if you go to
the T tools which is where uh you can um
use the apis to interact with the open
search um I'm once again not sure how
legible it is let me know if it is not
uh uh it is not okay
so uh let's
see good enough good
enough yeah no
okay so um uh the first thing that you
so uh Cat plugins tells me the list of
plugins I have the last one Ubi open
such Ubi plug is the plugin that you
want uh uh um so this needs to be
installed of course yeah and in order to
get started uh so this I have a sample
uh uh e-commerce data set uh index in
this open search uh uh cluster and I am
using the chorus open suchar Edition uh
uh repo if you are not familiar with it
uh the QR code has the link to this so
it basically I'm not
okay
see yeah so uh this basically is uh
let's go to the do compost it basically
has u a data prepper that I showed you
it has uh open search it has uh open
search dashboards and it also has the
chorus UI uh which is basically this and
the data that you see in here is the
sample data that is indexed as a part of
this index yeah so a bunch of e-commerce
data sample
data um so in order to get started with
Ubi what you have to do is basically
this is a match all query which means a
star query bring everything yeah um and
what you have to do is basically
extension Ubi and a dummy not dummy but
an empty call which basically creates
these two indices uh the query index and
the events index with the said uh schema
so the standard schema is already
created for you for both the uh queries
index and the events
index um so this is I mean uh easy way
to get started but of course yeah I mean
you want if you want to have an extended
schema if you want to extend the schema
if you want to change it a little bit
you have to create it from the by
yourself and also if you want to have a
different uh sharting strategy because
this obviously is going to create with
the default sharting strategy which is
uh one primary one replica and before
you know your events index is actually
going to grow so you want to be careful
uh when you create an index yeah and and
in this example um this is just a such
call uh as you see here a query string
uh default uh field that I'm searching
here is title and I'm searching for
something search for iPhones from tap
tools and I did tell you that the Ubi
plugin is going to lock the search
request just like that but it's not
entirely true you still have to pass
this information uh to the in the Ubi
Clause right in the Ubi syntax um which
is basically query ID which is something
that you pass uh from the front end you
generate a query ID and you pass it uh
user query which is basically the search
term that uh the user has searched for
the search phrase the client ID uh to
identify the user the query attributes
for in this example is the application
uh name but of course if you okay so if
I execute the search all right so I have
the hits so hit one hit two and if you
collapse uh I get the query ID that was
passed as a part of this uh such request
yeah but of course you can also um let
open search create a query ID in this
case it is going to create a query
ID uh but the only thing is if you are
letting the plugin to create the query
ID uh you have to in order to track the
such Journey uh you have to reuse the
query ID as you see fit yeah in your
context what what does a user session
mean to you uh would dictate how you
want to reuse this query idea how much
uh of a reuse that you want to uh use
for this U query ID yeah so now that I
have generated a query ID right I would
uh so now I am searching against the Ubi
queries index yeah and if I
look up for this one I actually have the
entire query that that I used I also
have the three doc IDs that were sent uh
sent back because uh if you look at it
I'm only sending uh I'm only asking for
three documents in here so which means
it has only sent back three doc IDs and
the rest of the things right the query
the user query U and the query ID and
the client ID time stamp and so on and
so forth so this is how you populate the
Ubi queries index yeah and for the
events index uh like I said it is not
the plugins responsibility to log it it
is your responsibility to I mean also
for U queries that is partially your
responsibility in sending the
information uh but for the events
completely um it is independent of the
plugin that we have yeah so if you look
at this example hopefully it is speak
enough I go and I show you this so I
search for iPhone I click on this I did
click on it um because there is no
Details page for this dummy uh uh demo
site and if you look at it I actually
can see this endpoint go going to my
data prepper and the request body uh the
payload is basically uh just as you saw
in the command so the action name the
product was clicked uh the client ID uh
to identify the user and the query ID
which is the same query ID that probably
either generated by Ubi for iPhone or
the one that you created in the front
end so I mean if you want like I said in
order to identify the um uh qu uh okay
never mind let me not go there yeah so
now let's say um I uh as a user click on
a bunch of filters let's say I'm using
the facet filter
which is once again in this context uh
is a separate suchar query so which is
why you can see another M search
happening and if you scroll enough you
should be able to see
the extension Ubi stuff and stuff yeah
so but hopefully you saw you oh it's too
tiny yeah
yeah so uh you can see here um yeah so
this is the Ubi information that uh your
front end is sending and I also let's
say um now I click on uh add to card or
or you can also cons I mean um you can
also let's say consider this button
click as a adding to my favorites so now
if you look at uh the events you see the
brand filter was clicked and
the product item was clicked at to cart
was clicked uh and I mean positive which
is basically let's say add to card so
this is how you send the information so
you just post the information to open
search now going back uh to open search
now you should be able to see uh the
different things that we just
did uh you can see the product click you
can see the let's say adding to the
favorites um you can see once again a
product click and so on and so forth so
everything that we did uh is already
persisted uh in open search
um yes so uh so this is how you
basically populate both the Ubi queries
index and the events
index um and at this point you are pop
uh you you are you have already
collected the data or you already have
streamlined a process to collect the
data so the next thing is and analyzing
the collected data right um so now we I
would show you a dashboard that we have
that was built um this is the dashboard
that was built um uh yeah so uh one of
the pie charts explaining um uh a pie
chart based on action name Yeah so
basically this is uh the different
actions that were that were performed uh
in the in the span of last one year
uh brand filter add to card just 1.6%
you can already know how much of add to
card contributes to the entire actions
that are performed by the users um
another uh visualization for uh the uh
click positions another visualization
for um uh the profit
margin for the trending Searchers or the
most popular searches with at least one
result or overall uh uh popular
searchers
uh session duration probably a
visualization built on top of the client
ID or maybe even session ID because uh
you can basically extend the schema like
I said
yeah and another chart for let's say um
price uh the amount spent by client uh
ID so who spending a lot so um so
someone is dropping serious cash in this
dummy e-commerce website yeah and and
this is already available for you uh in
the documentation if you go uh the
dashboards uh the open search Ubi
documentation you can already uh
download this ndjs file uh and import it
as a object into your open search
dashboards which means you can already
readily have this dashboard yeah of
course it for some of you who are
already familiar with let's say Keana or
open source dashboards this probably is
very uh
uh easy I would say but let's say for
someone who is getting started yeah uh
with Ubi uh at least yeah you can start
importing it and start visualizing uh
your data just like that right um
another motivating factor to use the
standardized schema and not going um uh
off track is basically you can reuse
that are being developed by someone else
so someone else is developing the
putting it uh out there uh with the
proper licensing so you can just like
that use it because the schema that you
and them are probably uh the same the
ones that are used yeah so I also
managed to create another visualization
for the longtail queries yeah goes to
say that it is pretty uh straightforward
to create the visualizations to uh get
insights from your user Behavior data
yeah so another thing that I wanted to
quickly show you is uh notebooks is
where uh is is kind of reporting in open
search uh you can create reports but
what I want to show here is how you can
use uh the SQL uh Handler in open search
to um analyze the uh collected data in
an adoc manner so let's say you have uh
product managers or Executives um
let's say non technical users but just
enough to know SQL but you don't have
time to create visualization for
them uh but they want to quickly look at
some information right uh with the user
Behavior data so SQL um is I would say a
universal language so this is a bunch of
some examples of how you can use SQL to
analyze the uh ingested data uh longtail
uh searches pretty simple uh SQL query
uh you also have the trending searches
once again you can add in the work
Clause Tim stamp to see the trending
searches in the last 6 hours or 12 hours
or 24 hours or whatnot
yeah uh this is the uh group buy by
action name which is basically the pie
chart that you just saw yeah and um
sample search Journey uh based on the
query ID uh for both the queries index
and the events
index and the session uh um based on the
client ID so these queries are already
available for you in the uh
documentation but uh no not this one
yeah but yeah I mean this goes to say
how easy it is to get started with uh
Ubi
yeah so now going back uh to the
presentation um the art of the
possibilities
um I mean uh you you all some of you are
probably using some of some kind of
secondary rer rankers uh learning to
rank or uh you're also probably using
learning to boost or meta rank or Amazon
personaliz uh for most of the thing that
are in here the common denominator is an
uh judgment list yeah so I attempted to
create uh with SQL uh um a basic uh
judgment list uh if you look at it it is
basically uh joining the queries index
and the events index with the using the
query ID as the joining factor and I'm
grading it based on let's say if action
name if all the three actions such as
item was clicked uh added to card and
purchased uh I'm I'm saying it this
particular doc ID is super relevant if
only two of the items or two of the
actions are performed it is slightly
less relevant but still relevant if only
one is performed I'm grading it to one
one if none of them is performed I'm
grading it to zero and with this pretty
straightforward SQL I'm able to create
ajustment list yeah so this is the uh I
mean this SQL probably is not going to
work in open search I I attempted it uh
but this is just to show you the idea um
you could also consider using let's say
um uh using the Hadoop client open
Hadoop client uh to let's say create
data frames for your Ubi queries and
your Ubi index uh queries and the events
index and write join queries uh in there
yeah so that's also a
possibility inside uh uh dashboards we
already saw how you can use uh uh the
dashboards to get gather
Insight um you can also write SQL query
but the SQL query lacks the
visualization in open search so what we
also have uh uh is a a query syntax
called PPL
uh folks familiar with Splunk probably
can easily understand what PPL is um uh
but the the difference is that with PPL
you can actually create visualizations
uh for the equivalence equal query but
still create visualizations yeah um uh
so one thing that I want to also point
out is um at some point I was telling
you about how the events index probably
there's a very good chance that it is
going to grow
uh grow good enough or big enough to
actually be bigger than your actual
inventory index or maybe even multiple
FS so at some point you have to think
about cost uh uh to save all this data
to store all this data let's say if
you're storing it for an year or two so
in open SE we have what we call uh a
warm node which is
basically uh storing uh older data acing
older data in a cheaper um cheaper
uh instance type um storage dense
instance type so you can write policies
to move your older data to uh uh cheaper
uh devices so hence uh that way you can
cut cost uh another uh thing that you
can think about is writing um using
rollups uh in open search to roll up
your uh older indices uh so you create a
summary index of your older index so you
the granularity but you still retain
enough information uh to do Trend
analysis yeah um so I know I'm saying
rollups here but I'm using transform
here I had some problems but this is
just to give you an idea and I managed
to shrink uh as you can see the size uh
of how much we are able to shrink
yeah um inside uh so slicing and dicing
the data with SQL is something that we
already saw um another thing that you
can do is use anomaly detection that is
available with open search or maybe even
uh uh outside uh open search so you can
so since these are time series data you
can use anomaly detection to find let's
say um uh for zero resar or trending
search as let's say there's a Tik Tok
video going viral and everyone is trying
to buy a same product but you do not
have it uh this is something that you
can capture uh as it happens and you can
let's say scramble to do something about
yeah um ating I mean uh B minimum you
can also think about using a lotting uh
to set some thresholds uh and get alerts
when uh such a thing meets a certain uh
threshold
yeah uh May testing um uh I would rra
and I think I missed one other thing um
so I mean we did see uh the how Ubi
provides Tate the uh user Behavior
metrix that it provides uh we also
looked at the standardizing the schema
uh the Ubi search uh Ubi for open search
and Beyond I think this is the one that
I missed uh maybe I have two or two or
three more minutes I want to quickly
talk about it and I want anyone who
already know about Ubi to challenge me
because this was something that I
thought I I realized uh when I was
looking into this which is basically
this right so um UB at this point is
only available with open search but
let's say I mean not everyone in here is
probably using open search you are using
uh several sear engines out there you're
probably using one of them um I know Ubi
the the plan is also to have uh the
interested parties interested search
engines to integrate uh or Implement Ubi
in it so you can start using it but then
um as I was saying right the Ubi events
has no um uh dependency on the Ubi
plugin with open search so which which
basically means if you're using any
other search engine you still can use
the Ubi plugin uh Ubi with open search
for your events index so the only thing
is the Ubi uh queries right because the
plug-in takes care of logging
it I'm thinking but uh let's say I mean
you can continue to use your search
engine as you do today but let's say if
you're using sor in this case right I
can still pass the entire solar query in
this query uh syntax right and still
would be able to lock the search query
the only missing thing here would be the
doc IDs that were sent back uh as a part
of the search qu because of course your
open search does not have your data but
what you can also do is um instead of
using the Ubi plugin to send this data
to uh open search you can treat it also
as an events and once the search is uh
return uh let's say when you're using
solar the search is now return you also
have the information on the doc IDs that
were written you can still put them back
uh to open search
yeah this is what I mean by um Beyond uh
so which means you can use technically
uh uh Ubi already and do not have to
wait for Ubi to be implemented uh in
your search engine or whatever that may
be yeah
uh so yeah so this is all I have and
before I say my thank you uh we are
working on an RFC uh a feature uh what
we saw so far is the this portion of it
is what we saw um uh which is basically
collecting the data and then getting
some insights uh so you can take uh uh
actions based on it or create Jud
judgment list based on it but the the
next uh taking it to the next step what
we are planning to do is um creating
automated uh uh uh implicit judgments
and also based on that uh sampling the
queries from the already collected Ubi
queries and then create uh such metrics
uh uh uh ndcg or any other such metric
so all this can be automated So Daniel
here at some point Daniel from o at some
point is going to talk about this
hopefully uh and he would give you a
detailed uh picture of this one uh so
what we are looking for is um if you
think this is valuable or if you think
that can certain things that can be
added so we want to build the right
thing right so yeah um yeah with this I
would say thank you very much and I hope
I am on time yeah perfect thank you
Ash and and just to add to that I just
like to extend my thanks from the OC
team because one of the interesting
things about working on this plugin with
with open search is their willingness to
make this a truly open schema an open
specification it's all open source and
not to just say this is just an open
search thing this is a potential way for
any search engine to log what users do
with the results and for all of us as
search Engineers to build something
together that makes our life easier
gives us the data we need to make search
better so I think that's a a fantastic
very exciting opportunity
so we've got some questions from online
but I'm going to start in the room do
anyone have a question for
as right I think this is the the first
one
here hi uh you mentioned about the query
ID and uh you briefly mentioned how you
can reuse it or whatever uh but I'm
thinking from uh context of type ahead
search does your schema are you
designing your schema so that you know
uh we can capture insights and keep them
uh and have all the kind of you know we
we'll have different kinds of metrics uh
that we want to calculate over a typing
session right and uh a type ahead search
uh will have its own you know uh those
kinds of things so how do you think that
the schema is
already uh capable of capturing all that
or do you have plans already to extend
the schema okay so the way I see it is
um
um when you use typ a head when the user
is using a typ a head and when they
click on it this is an event uh for the
events metric so that's how you capture
that typ Ahad has been used but on the
such um on the queries index you
wouldn't have this information you don't
need this information because a query ID
is going to be the same for the chosen
uh suggestion and uh that query ID would
also be locked
uh for the record that says that the typ
ofad was
used so you should be able
to get this information from these two
indices yeah uh does that make
sense yeah okay great thank you okay
we've got an online question here from
Tobias um the detailed data from Ubi be
very useful for teams who want to train
ml models what's the best way to get
that data You' be interested in uh out
of the open search database as a kind of
data
product o yeah I mean um for things like
let's say matter rank or AWS uh Amazon
personalized actually require the click
metrics
um I mean that is true I mean you can of
course use let's say in open S we have a
scroll API or we also have a uh we are
recommending to use suchar after in sort
of scroll these days but there are ways
to export data from open search um uh in
a large volume
um yeah so there are means to export
this data in large volume maybe also in
real time to put that data in any other
service or uh open source uh software
that you use to uh train your models
yeah so that is completely possible yeah
okay and and maybe just you know the
specifics there we can drop into the uh
into slack or something yes
um okay so do we have another question
from the room there was somebody over
here
yes thank you uh just a quick question
on the versioning uh the Obi plugin is
it available for the latest 2.17 version
for open search or is it for 2.15 as
well the question is for since when
compatibility of the plugin so I believe
the first cut the first uh release was
214 uh what I show was 215 so I it's
quite safe to say that anything after
215 you probably can start uh using it
so uh every uh version has the plug-in
version compatible plug-in version also
released so you have to use the
appropriate version
yeah okay um I think we've got time for
another quick question online uh so uh
Deb BR asks um how do you take care of
an explosion of events now many entries
and the events for the users persistent
clicking activities yeah I mean um I I I
I predominantly work on the log
analytics in open SS and the mapping
explosion is the number one problem or
at least one of the biggest problem that
I see the way I see it is uh as any
other mapping problem you have to be
conservative you have to find the
balance between being conservative and
being flexible in the sense you want to
pick a field which you are if you're
unsure of a certain field maybe it can
go inside but if you're sure that this
is a field that you're not going to use
or hardly going to use then you have to
really question if it has value if if if
storing the data for a long time which
is also going to cost you uh if if it
adds value or not yeah so yeah I mean it
really comes down to using our judgments
to see uh and also okay maybe another
better way to look at it is uh to use a
uh a mapping that is not Dynamic you
define what you want you must Define
what goes in your mapping and not let
the dynamic mapping create whatever
field that you are sending in because
that is going to be quote unquote
dangerous
yeah okay thank you very much Ashworth
okay thank you very much yeah